Todd A. Murphy

I am currently an Information Technology major with a Specialization in Network and Information Security. I am very experienced with electronics, computers and especially networking. In my free time, I enjoy designing circuits, printing them onto circuits boards and soldering components just so I can have another smart device controlled by Siri. As I continue my studies at NJIT, I plan on double-specializing in IT (Network & Information Security and Web Applications).











Sewell, NJ

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science in Information Technology

New Jersey Institute of TechnologyNewark, NJ
GPA 3.91
Expected Graduation: May 2020

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE =

Technician

NJIT Media Services

Fall 2016 – Present

Newark, NJ

- Delivered and assembled all computer, sound and video related hardware for special events
- Experienced in troubleshooting technical problems, especially under pressure

Show Technician

Spellcaster Productions

June 2015 - Present

Hammonton, NJ

- Managed the safety on any project and ensured an adequate and clean working environment
- Generated advertisements in order to increase the clientele and made templates for cost estimates

Stagehand

I.A.T.S.E. Local 8

September 2014 – Present

Philadelphia, PA

- Responsible for all behind-the-scenes tech during live shows
- · Operated many sound consoles, lighting consoles, and spotlights
- Experienced in being a backstage coordinator

Sound Engineer

Investors Bank Performing Arts Center September 2012 – June 2016 Washington Township, NJ

- Leader of the Technical Crew
- Responsible for the operation of multiple Allen & Heath Sound Consoles
- Successfully put on many shows involving many different sound arrays

Manager/Ice Maker

Rita's Water Ice

September 2005 – Present

Hammonton, NJ

- Responsible for running the family business as lead manager
- Experienced in making water ice, waiting on customers and counting registers

LEADERSHIP EXPERIENCE -

John O. Mosely Leadership School

Sigma Alpha Epsilon

July 2017

Phoenix, Arizona

 Explored leadership abilities, learned new skills and interacted with interesting undergraduates and alumni from around the Realm of Sigma Alpha Epsilon.

AFFILIATIONS -

Treasurer & Webmaster

Sigma Alpha Epsilon Fraternity

Spring 2017 - Present

SOFTWARE -

- Photoshop
- Illustrator
- Fusion 360
- Word, Excel, PowerPoint
- Unity
- Android Studio
- Xcode
- Wireshark
- Experienced in macOS, Linux & Windows

COMPUTER LANGUAGES =

- Python
- C++
- JAVA
- HTML & CSS
- C#: Unity
- JavaScriptPHP
- Swift
- 1111
- Arduino
- SQL

PERSONAL PROJECTS -

DIY HomeKit Enabled LED's

Siri-enabled lights from scratch.

Sigma Alpha Epsilon – NJIT Website

Designed saenjit.com

WEBSITES



/tmurphy605



HTTP://TODDAMURPHY.ME